Was Shakespeare a Fraud?
Anonymous is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Roland Emmerich.
Set against the backdrop of the succession of Queen Elizabeth I, and the Essex Rebellion against her, the story
advances the theory that it was in fact Edward De Vere, Earl of Oxford who penned Shakespeare's plays.
Young Earl of Oxford, played by Jamie Campbell Bower.
Edward de Vere, played by Rhys Ifans.
William Cecil, played by David Thewlis.
Princess Elizabeth Tudor, played by Joely Richardson.
Queen Elizabeth I, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Ben Jonson, played by Sebastian Armesto.
Anonymous is a 2011 period drama film directed by
Roland Emmerich and written by John Orloff.
The film is a fictionalized version of the life of Edward de Vere, 17th Earl of Oxford, an Elizabethan courtier,
playwright, poet and patron of the arts, and suggests he was the actual author of William Shakespeare's plays.
It stars Rhys Ifans as de Vere and Vanessa Redgrave
as Queen Elizabeth I of England.
The film premiered at the Toronto International
Film Festival on September 11, 2011.
Produced by Centropolis Entertainment and Studio Babelsberg and distributed by Columbia Pictures, Anonymous was released on October 28,
2011 in the United States, Canada and the United Kingdom, expanding to theatres around the world in the following weeks.
The film performed poorly at the box office and received mixed reviews from critics for praising its performances and visual achievements, but
criticising the film's time-jumping format, factual errors, and promotion of the Oxfordian theory of Shakespeare authorship.
The film explores themes of anonymity, politics, poet,
duringcreditsstinger, false history.
The tone is emotional and intense.